Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1929-(1978-1982)-1984; Accession 1986-M-053; 7.75 linear feet (15 boxes)
  - Correspondence, Series I
    - General
      - New York Sunday Times Book Review (Box 193, Folder 169)
      - The New Yorker, 1967 (Box 193, Folder 170)
      - Nilson, Don, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 171)
      - O'Neill, Thomas (Tip); William O'Neill, 1981, undated (Box 193, Folder 172)
      - Orrman, E., 1978 (Box 193, Folder 173)
      - Oxford University Press, 1979, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 174)
      - Page, Norman, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 175)
      - Pao-ho Liang, Thomas, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 176)
      - Paolera, Felix della, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 177)
      - Parisi, Peter, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 178)
      - Partisan Review, 1981-1982 (Box 193, Folder 179)
      - Paschall, Douglas, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 180)
      - Pathfinder Press, 1977 (Box 193, Folder 181)
      - Pendergast, Patrick, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 182)
      - Phillips, Robert, 1981-1982 (Box 193, Folder 183)
      - Polk, Leslie, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 184)
      - Pollet, Elizabeth, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 185)
      - Potter, Clarkson, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 186)
      - Prior, Moody, 1979-1981 (Box 193, Folder 187)
      - Random House, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 188)
      - Reiner, Marian, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 189)
      - Riesman, David, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 190)
      - Rikhoff, Jean, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 191)
      - Riley, Barbara, 1981 (Box 193, Folder 192)
      - Rivera, Valerie, 1983 (Box 193, Folder 193)
      - Robbins, Richard, 1979-1980 (Box 193, Folder 194)
      - Robinson, David, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 195)
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 196)
      - Rolls-Royce Motors, 1980 (Box 193, Folder 197)
      - Rossi, John, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 198)
      - Roth, Arthur, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 199)
      - Roussapoulos, Dimitri, undated (Box 193, Folder 200)
      - Rubin, Dana, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 201)
      - Russell, Frank, 1980, undated (Box 193, Folder 202)
      - Salisbury, Harrison, 1978-1979 (Box 193, Folder 203)
      - SANE Education Fund, 1978 (Box 193, Folder 204)
      - Schaffner, ______, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 205)
      - Schapiro, Meyer, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 206)
      - Schlesinger, Arthur, 1981-1982 (Box 193, Folder 207)
      - Schwartz, Delmore, 1945, undated (Box 193, Folder 208)
      - Schwartz, Kenneth, 1982 (Box 193, Folder 209)
      - Scott, Walter, 1979 (Box 193, Folder 210)
      - Shaw, Irwin, 1972, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 211)
      - Shawn, Bill, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 212)
      - Shea, Jo, 1975-1977 (Box 194, Folder 213)
      - Siegal, Fred, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 214)
      - Simmons, Willie, 1981-1982 (Box 194, Folder 215)
      - Simon & Schuster, 1978-1979 (Box 194, Folder 216)
      - Sisson, Jonathan, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 217)
      - Skidmore College, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 218)
      - Sklare, Arnold, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 219)
      - Smith, Annette Cox, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 220)
      - Smith, Page, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 221)
      - St. Martin's Press, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 222)
      - Statler, G. Chip, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 223)
      - Stern, Gloria, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 224)
      - Stewart, Thomas, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 225)
      - Still, Bayrd, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 226)
      - Stoehr, Taylor, 1979, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 227)
      - Stone, Richard, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 228)
      - Sullivan, Kathleen, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 229)
      - Taylor, Annabel, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 230)
      - Taylor, Harold, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 231)
      - Thomson, David, 1980, undated (Box 194, Folder 232)
      - Towers, Tom, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 233)
      - Trilling, Diana, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 234)
      - Tuchman, Phyllis, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 235)
      - Unidentified correspondence, first names (A-Z), 1964, 1967, 1977, 1978, 1980-1982, undated (Box 194, Folder 236-238)
      - Unidentified correspondence, no first names, 1969, 1970, 1980-1982, undated (Box 194, Folder 239)
      - University of California, 1969 (Box 194, Folder 240)
      - Van Ness, Wilhelmina, 1979, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 241)
      - Vicente, Harriet, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 242)
      - Vonnegut, Kurt, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 243)
      - Wald, Alan, 1976 (Box 194, Folder 244)
      - Walmsley, Margot, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 245)
      - War Resisters League, undated (Box 194, Folder 246)
      - Weeks, Robert, 1965 (Box 194, Folder 247)
      - Weinberg, Helen, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 248)
      - Weinberg, Herman, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 249)
      - Weiner, Lois, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 250)
      - Weldon, Kathy, n. d. (Box 194, Folder 251)
      - Wells, Dean Faulkner, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 252)
      - Wheatcroft, Geoffrey, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 253)
      - Wheeler, Dick, 1980-1981 (Box 194, Folder 254)
      - Wheeler, Lucy Pope, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 255)
      - Whitfield, Steve, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 256)
      - Who's Who in America, 1983 (Box 194, Folder 257)
      - Williams, Galen, undated (Box 194, Folder 258)
      - Wilkins, Sophie, 1979-1982 (Box 194, Folder 259)
      - Winnick, Roy, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 260)
      - Wise, Kelly, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 261)
      - Wolf, Howard, 1978-1979 (Box 194, Folder 262)
      - Woliheim, Day and Richard, 1974, n. d. (Box 194, Folder 263)
      - Wolz, Barbara, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 264)
      - Wyman, David, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 265)
      - Wynkoop, Gerardus, 1980 (Box 194, Folder 266)
      - Yale Daily News, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 267)
      - Yale University, 1978 (Box 194, Folder 268)
      - Yale University. Library., 1978-1979 (Box 194, Folder 269)
      - Yale University. Timothy Dwight College, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 270)
      - Yale University Press, 1982 (Box 194, Folder 271)
      - Young-Bruehl, Elisabeth, 1981 (Box 194, Folder 272)
      - Zahn, Gordon, 1979 (Box 194, Folder 273)
  - RESEARCH AND WRITING, Series II
    - Early writings
      - Cheer for the Class (includes reprints of 1927 articles by Macdonald), n. d. (Box 195, Folder 274)
      - Movies, [1930s] (Box 195, Folder 275-277)
      - Theatre -- "The Modem Theatre: An Inquest", 1930 (Box 195, Folder 278)
      - "U.S. Steel", 1936 (Box 195, Folder 279-280)
    - Subject files
      - Anarchism, undated (Box 196, Folder 281-282)
      - Beerbohm, Max: A Christmas Garland, 1975 (Box 196, Folder 283)
      - "Cocteau: Beauty and the Beast", undated (Box 196, Folder 284)
      - "Confessions of a Literary Journalist", 1977 (Box 196, Folder 285-286)
      - Eisenstein, Sergei, 1978 (Box 196, Folder 287-290)
      - Eisenstein, Sergei, 1978 (Box 197, Folder 291-298)
      - Fellini, undated (Box 197, Folder 299)
      - Fortune: 50th anniversary piece, 1979 (Box 197, Folder 300)
      - Gorky trilogy, undated (Box 197, Folder 301)
      - Harper Dictionary of Contemporary Usage (questionnaire response), n. d. (Box 197, Folder 302)
      - Keaton, Buster, 1980 (Box 197, Folder 303-306)
      - Kultur, undated (Box 197, Folder 307)
      - Kurosawa, undated (Box 197, Folder 308)
      - Mass culture, undated (Box 198, Folder 309-311)
      - Modern English usage, [1965] (Box 198, Folder 312-313)
      - Movies, 1979 (Box 198, Folder 314-316)
      - Naked Night, undated (Box 198, Folder 317)
      - New York City's intellectuals, undated (Box 198, Folder 318)
      - Old Left, New Left, 1970 (Box 199, Folder 319-320)
      - Ozu, Yasujiro, undated (Box 199, Folder 321)
      - Parodies, 1982 (Box 199, Folder 322-324)
      - Poe, Edgar Allan, undated (Box 199, Folder 325-329)
      - Poe, Edgar Allan, undated (Box 200, Folder 330-345)
      - Poe, Edgar Allan, undated (Box 201, Folder 346-348)
      - Renoir, Jean, undated (Box 201, Folder 349)
      - "Some notes on Pornographic Movies", undated (Box 201, Folder 350)
      - Utopians, n. d. (Box 201, Folder 351)
    - Shorter Writings
      - Hemingway, 1981 (Box 201, Folder 352)
      - Movies -- "Bad Movie Review", undated (Box 201, Folder 353)
      - Myths, undated (Box 201, Folder 354)
      - Students for a Democratic Society fundraising appeal, 1968 (Box 201, Folder 355)
  - TEACHING AND LECTURES, Series III
    - Aspen Design Conference, 1964 (Box 202, Folder 356)
    - Aspen Institute lectures, 1978 (Box 202, Folder 357)
    - California, University of, at San Diego, 1977 (Box 202, Folder 358)
    - John Jay College (correspondence, notes and syllabi), 1974-1976 (Box 202, Folder 359-361)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo (correspondence and course materials), 1973-1974 (Box 202, Folder 362-363)
    - State University of New York at Buffalo (lecture notes), 1980 (Box 202, Folder 364)
    - Texas, University of (lecture notes and drafts), 1966 (Box 202, Folder 365)
    - Yale University (talk about), undated (Box 202, Folder 366)
    - Yale University. Drama School (correspondence, seminar notes), 1977-1978 (Box 202, Folder 367-368)
    - "Yale 1928 and 1978: My Yale to Your Yale" (Box 202, Folder 369)
  - MISCELLANY, Series IV
    - Interviews
      - Brown, Skip, letter re interview, 1974 (Box 202, Folder 370)
      - Brown, Skip, interview, 1974 April; 1 (Box 207)
        Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
      - Sayne, N. (transcript of interview), undated (Box 202, Folder 371)
      - Unidentified, n. d.; 1 (Box 208)
    - Legal and Financial
      - Bank statements and check logs (including cancelled checks), 1969-1979 (Box 203, Folder 372-380)
      - Income tax returns, 1975-1978 (Box 204, Folder 381-383)
      - Insurance and health care forms, 1937, 1970-1981 (Box 204, Folder 384)
      - Investment and financial information, 1980-1981 (Box 204, Folder 385)
      - Royalties income and financial information, 1977-1980 (Box 204, Folder 386)
      - Royalties and permissions, 1978-1979 (Box 204, Folder 387)
      - Royalty requests and statements, 1968-1980 (Box 204, Folder 388-389)
      - Social security information, 1978-1979 (Box 204, Folder 390)
      - Tax and financial information, 1978-1979 (Box 204, Folder 391)
      - Tenant disputes, 1976-1978 (Box 204, Folder 392-393)
    - Personal
      - "Big Mystery Home", undated (Box 205, Folder 394)
      - Birth certificate, 1931 (Box 205, Folder 395)
      - Diary fragment, 1978 (Box 205, Folder 396)
      - Dream -- Gandhi, 1981 (Box 205, Folder 397)
    - Delmore Schwartz
      - Correspondence, 1967, 1980-1982 (Box 205, Folder 398)
      - Schwartz estate, 1967, 1980-1982 (Box 205, Folder 399-400)
      - Writings, 1979,1981, undated (Box 205, Folder 401-406)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS, Series V
    - General (includes Dwight Macdonald, Macdonald family, and Buster Keaton), undated (Box 205, Folder 407)
    - Delmore Schwartz, undated (Box 205, Folder 408)
  - PREVIOUSLY RESTRICTED FILES
    - Macdonald, Dwight
      - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, 1978 (Box 206, Folder 409)
      - Medical information, 1977-1984 (Box 206, Folder 410-416)
    - Macdonald, Gloria
      - note re "A Summary", undated (Box 206, Folder 417)
      - Personal correspondence, 1957, 1973, undated (Box 206, Folder 418)